A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Public/private Ventures (09300964), 1993 May 01-2001 October 31 (Reel R9150)
    Support for analysis of programs that enable low-income urban residents to travel to areas of strong job growth
    $2,835,000.00; $2,835,000.00
    Manus, Mara A.; Elliott, Mark D.
  - Public/private Ventures (09301262), 1993 August 01-1997 January 31 (Reel R7333)
    Support for strengthening social infrastructure for successful teenage development and transition to adulthood.
    United States; Youth--Services for--United States
  - Public/private Ventures (09350118), 1992 November 01-1993 February 28 (Reel R6447)
    Support for an in-depth assessment of leading transportation-oriented anti-poverty programs
  - Public/private Ventures (09600580), 1996 January 01-1997 June 30 (Reel R7626)
    Partial support for a study of voluntary youth-serving organizations
  - Public/private Ventures (09601023), 1996 July 01-1996 December 31 (Reel R7329)
    Support for exploration of options to influence states' implementation of the workforce development block grant
    Elliott, Mark D.; Mincy, Ronald B.; Mohamed, Inca A.
  - Public/private Ventures (09700578), 1997 January 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8923)
    Support to complete phase i of the community change for youth development demonstration project (930-1262)
    $1,850,000.00; $1,850,000.00
  - Public/private Ventures (09700910), 1997 April 01-2005 March 31 (Reel R9143)
    Technical assistance to states to improve their workforce development policies
    Human Development and Reproductive Health; Economic Development
    $2,795,000.00; $2,795,000.00
    Colborn, John L.; Mincy, Ronald B.
  - Public/private Ventures (09700911), 1997 April 01-1998 June 30 (Reel R7971)
    Exploration of strategies to improve the knowledge and practice of effective workforce development (960-1023)
    Manus, Mara A.; Mincy, Ronald B.
  - Public/private Ventures (09701360), 1997 September 01-2003 September 30 (Reel R9197)
    Continued general support for planning, proposal development, executive staffing, and program coordination (850-0518)
    $2,050,000.00; $2,050,000.00
  - Public/private Ventures (09701520), 1997 July 01-2002 March 31 (Reel R8964)
    Support for an initiative to assist community-based networks of youth service programs that combine paid participants and volunteers
    Governance and Civil Society; KC & F - Office of the Vice President; Human Development and Reproductive Health
  - Public/private Ventures (09800680), 1998 March 01-2003 February 28 (Reel R9018)
    Endowment grant
  - Public/private Ventures (09800681), 1998 March 01-2003 February 28 (Reel R9024)
    Joint venture fund
    $3,500,000.00; $3,500,000.00
  - Public/private Ventures (09801655), 1998 August 01-2003 September 30 (Reel R9002)
    To coordinate and evaluate faith-based community and youth development programs in distressed metropolitan areas
    $2,550,000.00; $2,550,000.00
    United States; Austin (Tex.); Boston (Mass.); Church work with youth--United States; Youth--Services for--Texas--Austin (Tex.); Youth--Services for--New York (State)--New York (N.Y.)
  - Public/private Ventures (09851602), 1998 July 01-2000 June 30 (Reel R8200, Reel R8259)
    Support its youth development directions project
  - Public/private Ventures (09901037), 1999 June 01-2000 May 31 (Reel R8876)
  - Public/private Ventures (10101249), 2001 May 01-2004 April 30 (Reel R9175)
    For Operation 2006, a violence-prevention program for at-risk youth
  - Public/private Ventures (10101597), 2001 June 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R8937)
    To explore the feasibility of expanding PPV's faith-based prevention programs for at-risk youth
    Duncan, Cynthia M.; Campbell, Elizabeth C.
    United States; Church and social problems -- United States; Mentoring in church work--United States
  - Publishing Center For Cultural Resources, Inc. (07650226), 1976 January 01-1978 December 31 (Reel R2694)
    Support to continue and expand advisory work relating to educational publications
  - Pueblo of Zuni (09200833), 1992 May 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8325)
    Support to assist the zuni tribe to develop a plan for sustainable agriculture
    New Mexico
  - Puerto Rastrojo Foundation Biology Station (08800635), 1988 April 01-1995 June 30 (Reel R7054, Reel R7808)
    Support to implement a resource management plan in the colombian amazon
    $276,000.00; $276,000.00
    Chiel, David; Varas, Augusto
  - Puerto Rastrojo Foundation Biology Station (09600929), 1996 July 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8311)
    Dissemination of recommended resource management practices and policies for a protected area in the colombian amazon
    $140,080.00; $140,080.00
  - Puerto Rican Association for Community Affairs, Inc. (09951315), 1999 January 01-1999 December 31 (Reel R8261)
    Partial support for a seven-site video conference, scheduled for october 15, 1999, to discuss the impact of recent federal family and child welfare legislation on the puerto rican community
    Puerto Rico; Connecticut; Illinois; Family policy -- United States; Child welfare -- Law and legislation -- United States
  - Puerto Rican Association for Community Affairs, Inc. (10051392), 2000 June 01-2001 January 31 (Reel R8751)
    Planning grant to develop the institute for applied research, a policy ananlysis center focused on the particular needs of puerto rican and latino families
    United States; Family policy -- United States; Family -- Economic aspects -- United States; Hispanic Americans
  - Puerto Rican Family Institute, Inc. (07950481), 1979 June 15-1980 June 14 (Reel R2963)
    Support for personnel and consultancy expenses in conjunction withresearch on return migration
  - Puerto Rican Family Institute, Inc. (08450028), 1983 November 01-1984 April 30 (Reel R4383)
    Support of a conference on the needs of migrating puerto rican families and the adequacy of governmental services to meet them
    $26,647.00; $26,647.00
    Puerto Rico; New York (N.Y.)
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (07300089), 1972 December 20-1996 December 31 (Reel R7154, Reel R7155, Reel R8489)
    Litigation, advocacy & educational outreach re: voting rights, housing, employment, economic justice, education & latina rights
    $32,480,000.00; $32,480,000.00
    Romero, Anthony D.; Cuevas, Christina
    United States; Education, Bilingual
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense And Education Fund, Inc. (07650119), 1976 January 01-1976 August 31 (Reel R2595)
    Support for a teaching conference for lawyers concerning lawsuits relating to bilingual education
    Bohrson, Ralph G.; Martus, Marjorie
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (08150134), 1980 December 01-1981 May 31 (Reel R2693)
    To support a study of social service and job training programs for puerto rican female heads-of-household in nyc
    $6,670.00; $6,670.00
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (08150390), 1981 April 01-1981 November 30 (Reel R2897)
    To support phase ii of study of programs for puerto rican female heads-of-household in nyc
    $12,190.00; $12,190.00
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (08400381), 1984 April 01-1985 March 31 (Reel R5286)
    To enable fund to relocate and participate in the public interest law center
    $99,285.00; $99,285.00
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (08500693), 1985 April 01-1987 December 31 (Reel R5296)
    Support for activities to facilitate a smooth leadership transition & strengthen and diversity fundraising initiatives
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (09500657), 1995 March 01-1996 February 29 (Reel R6795)
    Support to assist u.s. Women's groups to prepare for and participate in the fourth world conference on women in beijing, china
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (09650628), 1996 April 01-1997 March 31 (Reel R7340)
    Support for deficit reduction
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (09700431), 1997 January 01-2003 November 30 (Reel R9168)
    Support for civil rights litigation and advocacy, and organizational development activities
    $2,175,000.00; $2,175,000.00
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10000887), 2000 April 01-2002 March 31 (Reel R9027)
    Support for litigation, advocacy, research, and education on latino voting rights in the decennial redistricting process
    United States; Apportionment (Election law) -- United States; Voting research--United States; Hispanic Americans -- Political activity
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10100960), 2001 April 01-2001 November 30 (Reel R9001)
    Support for a Fund-sponsored network of U.S. NGOs coordinating participation in World Conference Against Racism
    United States; Human rights; Intergroup relations -- Congresses; Ethnic relations -- Congresses
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10101791), 2001 May 01-2001 September 30 (Reel R9092)
    To plan and launch an environmental justice project to address the environmental harm suffered by Latinos in New York City, the northeastern United States and Puerto Rico
    Miller-Travis, Vernice
    Puerto Rico; New York (State); Northeastern States; Environmental justice -- Puerto Rico; Environmental justice -- New York (N.Y.)
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10200944), 2002 April 01-2004 March 31 (Reel R9083)
    Start-up support for a Latino Environmental Justice Project
    Puerto Rico; New York (State); Northeastern States; Environmental justice -- Puerto Rico; Environmental justice -- New York (State) -- New York (State)
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10350259), 2002 December 01-2003 November 30 (Reel R9086)
    To address the funding shortfall arising from the purchase and renovation of office space
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10350694), 2003 March 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9093)
    For organizational efforts to ease the transition of leadership following the departure of its President and General Counsel
  - Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (10351271), 2003 July 01-2004 June 30 (Reel R9089)
    To restructure the fund's programs, institute emergency fundraising procedures and cover a funding shortfall as its searches for and transitions to new leadership
    Jenkins, Alan; Rios, Sara
  - Puerto Rican Migration Research Consortium, Inc. (07800232), 1978 February 01-1979 June 30 (Reel R2271)
    Administrative and fellowship support for a research project on puerto rican migration
    $117,088.73; $117,088.73
    Oppenheimer-Nicolau, Siobhan; Payton, Benjamin Franklin
  - Puerto Rican Traveling Theatre Company, Inc. (07900695), 1979 October 01-1983 September 30 (Reel R4530)
    Transitional support of their movement into an enlarged permanent theater space
  - Puerto Rican Traveling Theatre Company, Inc. (08800946), 1988 October 01-1991 September 30 (Reel R6273)
    Support for a marketing and development effort
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (08500357), 1985 March 01-1988 December 31 (Reel R5883, Reel R5884)
    General support for administration, grantmaking and the possible creation of an endownment
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (08900976), 1989 September 01-1994 December 31 (Reel R7490, Reel R7491)
    Endowment support
    Rights And Social Justice Program [RSJ]; Governance And Public Policy Program [GPP]
    Diaz, William A.; Seltzer, Michael
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09100302), 1990 October 01-1992 May 31 (Reel R6606)
    Fundraising support
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09101325), 1991 September 01-1994 August 31 (Reel R6913)
    Partial support for a program of technical assistance to the st. Croix foundation for community development
    Puerto Rico; United States Virgin Islands
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09200997), 1992 July 01-1993 October 31 (Reel R6415)
    Project support for a history of the puerto rico community foundation
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09300888), 1993 July 01-1997 December 31 (Reel R7543)
    Supplemental support for the puerto rico community foundation's program, support system for the arts
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09400754), 1994 May 01-1998 September 30 (Reel R7919)
    Support to expand fundraising development activities
    Seltzer, Michael
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09501190), 1995 September 01-1999 July 31 (Reel R8373)
    Support for a planning process to develop a community development funding partnership
    $1,075,000.00; $1,075,000.00
    Roman, Ruth
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09550574), 1994 August 01-1995 July 31 (Reel R6666)
    Support for planning and organizing a conference for foundation supported community development collaboratives
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09650293), 1995 November 01-1996 October 31 (Reel R7541)
    Support for strategic planning
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09750281), 1996 December 01-1997 November 30 (Reel R7355, Reel R7465)
    Support for regional participation in the january 20-22, 1997 international conference on community philanthropy in puerto rico
    Tillett, Anthony D.
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09900360), 1999 January 01-1999 December 31 (Reel R8271)
    Support for enhancement of nonprofit organizations in puerto rico following hurricane george
    Puerto Rico; Disaster relief -- Puerto Rico
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (09901238), 1999 September 01-2001 August 31 (Reel R8880)
    To build the capacity of the consortium for community economic development in puerto rico to provide technical assistance, training, grants, and loans to community development organizations
    Gilbert, Linetta
    Puerto Rico; Community development -- Puerto Rico
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (10101612), 2001 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R9076)
    For planning, analysis and organizational development in preparation for a major new endowment campaign
    Puerto Rico; Humanitarianism--Puerto Rico
  - Puerto Rico Community Foundation (10201619), 2002 June 01-2004 May 31 (Reel R9160)
    General support to expand the role of local philanthropy in promoting and sustaining community development and for outreach activities to increase its endowment
  - Puerto Rico Department Of Education (06300184), 1963 March 15-1967 September 14 (Reel R2770, Reel R2771)
    Program to improve the education of teachers and the curriculum in secondary schools
    $650,000.00; $618,657.80
  - Puerto Rico Department Of Education (06500147), 1965 July 01-1970 June 30 (Reel R1587)
    Curriculum centers designed to improve course offerings for public elementary and secondary school teachers
    $750,000.00; $622,075.97
  - Puerto Rico Department Of Education (06700534), 1967 July 01-1968 June 30 (Reel R2310)
    Planning exemplary school complexes to be funded by the federal government
  - Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs (08000167), 1979 November 01-1982 October 31 (Reel R3545)
    Partial support for the summer 1980 session of the international school on disarmament and research on conflicts (osodarco)
  - Punjab Agricultural University (07100467), 1971 August 01-1977 October 14 (Reel R2901)
    Support for the development of the university's college of agricultural engineering
    $266,198.00; $266,198.00
    Havener, Robert D.; Petit, Michael J.
  - Punjab Agricultural University (08450455), 1984 April 16-1986 June 30 (Reel R5379)
    Support for a workshop on management of groundwater resources in irrigated areas (india)
    $5,300.00; $875.31
    Bottrall, Anthony
  - Purdue Research Foundation (06000035), 1959 November 24-1966 March 28 (Reel R0205, Reel R0206, Reel R0207)
    Midwest program on airborne television instruction
    $14,672,000.00; $14,672,000.00
  - Purdue Research Foundation (06300142), 1963 February 07-1965 February 06 (Reel R0277)
    Incorporation of a commission on engineering education
  - Purdue Research Foundation (06300211), 1963 April 24-1968 April 23 (Reel R0382)
    Study of chinese and japanese by beginner and intermediate students
    $256,000.00; $256,000.00
  - Purdue Research Foundation (06500120), 1965 February 25-1970 February 24 (Reel R1590)
    Faculty and doctoral research in the krannert graduate school of industrial administration
  - Purdue Research Foundation (06700051), 1967 January 10-1970 January 09 (Reel R1809, Reel R1810)
    Summer institutes for intensive study of chinese and japanese at member univs of committee on inst. Cooperation
    $230,000.00; $229,715.54
    Finkelstein, David J.
  - Push For Excellence, Inc. (07900033), 1978 November 22-1982 January 31 (Reel R3760)
    Partial support for an experimental program for community-school improvement, project excel
    $275,600.00; $275,600.00
  - Push for Excellence, Inc. (08300180), 1982 September 01-1983 August 31 (Reel R4573)
    Support to the national push/excel office to shift from centralized to decentralized management of its program
  - Pyramid Communications Inc. (09500653), 1995 May 01-1997 April 30 (Reel R7202)
    To help plan meetings and other collaborative activities among organizations concerned with environment and development issues
  - Pyramid Communications Inc. (09550487), 1995 January 01-1995 December 31 (Reel R6980)
  - Pyramid Communications Inc. (09700636), 1997 March 01-1999 February 28 (Reel R8065)
    To develop a comprehensive communications strategy on conservation-based community development
  - Qianxi Women's Federation, Hebei Province (09501372), 1995 August 15-2004 June 30 (Reel R9201)
    General support for legal services for rural women
    $584,000.00; $584,000.00
  - Qianxi Women's Federation, Hebei Province (10250938), 2002 April 01-2003 September 30 (Reel R9238)
    For activities to promote women's participation in village government
  - Qianxi Women's Federation, Hebei Province (10351354), 2003 August 01-2006 July 31 (Reel R9212)
    For advocacy and training on using the newly enacted Rural Land Contract Law to protect the land tenure rights of Chinese women
  - Qingdao Bureau of Civil Affairs (10151726), 2001 July 01-2002 June 30 (Reel R8846)
    For research and publication documenting urban community development and local government reform in Qingdao
    China; Local Political science--China--Reform; Urban policy--China; Community development -- China
  - Qinghai Normal University (10151723), 2001 June 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R8843)
    For a program of language strengthening for teachers in a poor county in Qinghai Province
    $19,400.00; $19,400.00
    China; English language -- Study and teaching -- China; Language and languages--Study and teaching--China; Teachers--Training of--China
  - Quaid-E-Azam University (07200145), 1972 March 10-1975 March 09 (Reel R1137, Reel R3132)
    Provision of a computer 360/44 for research and development
  - Quaid-E-Azam University (07300014), 1972 November 21-1977 June 30 (Reel R1237, Reel R4284)
    Provision of research equipment for laboratories
    $161,000.00; $161,000.00
    Cool, John C.; Frodin, Reuben
  - Quaid-E-Azam University (07350457), 1973 March 08-1973 May 07 (Reel R1644, Reel R4285)
    Pakistan history conference to be held in april 1973
    $1,010.00; $1,010.00
    Quinn, John A.
  - Quaid-E-Azam University (07500028), 1974 October 01-1977 June 30 (Reel R4464)
    Support for social sciences and cultural studies
    $180,800.00; $180,800.00
  - Quaid-E-Azam University (07700678), 1977 August 01-1984 July 31 (Reel R4537, Reel R5203, Reel R5374)
    Training and research in the field of anthropology
    $75,000.00; $71,533.79
  - Quan Consulting (08850497), 1988 February 01-1989 January 31 (Reel R5620)
    Planning grant to help establish hispanic development funds in several sites around the country
    United States; Fresno (Calif.); Los Angeles (Calif.); New York (N.Y.)
  - Queen Alia Jordan Social Welfare Fund (08150621), 1981 January 01-1982 January 31 (Reel R4047, Reel R5124)
    Consultant services for planning a social affairs unit
    Lesch, Ann M.
    Jordan
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (07200166), 1972 May 24-1974 December 31 (Reel R4352)
    Research project to study the interrelationship between defense and development
    Geithner, Peter F.; Schoettle, Enid C. B.
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (07400254), 1974 June 28-1986 June 30 (Reel R5061)
    Support a review of literature on various aspects of development
    $11,600.00; $11,600.00
    Carmichael, William D.(William Daniel); Schoettle, Enid C. B.
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (07950608), 1979 August 01-1981 July 31 (Reel R2512)
    Support of the activities of the oxford women's studies committee
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (08450271), 1984 March 01-1984 August 31 (Reel R4789, Reel R4891)
    Enable sudanese and other africans to attend symposium on "assistance to refugees: alternative viewpoints," oxford, england
    Developing Country Programs [DCP]; Middle East and North Africa (Cairo)
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (08650224), 1985 September 01-1986 August 31 (Reel R5214, Reel R5983)
    Technical assistance to the refugee studies program at the university of juba in the sudan
    $5,000.00; $.00
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (08750680), 1987 June 15-1989 June 14 (Reel R5795)
    Partial support for a workshop on food security issues
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (08850892), 1988 June 20-1989 September 30 (Reel R5755, Reel R5797)
    Support for 2 nigerian scholars as visiting fellows at the refugee studies programme
    $47,100.00; $46,560.00
    Hodges, Anthony D. C.
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (08850956), 1988 June 01-1988 November 30 (Reel R5802, Reel R5979)
    Support for an international symposium on palestinian refugees in the gaza strip and west bank
    $13,500.00; $13,500.00
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (08851032), 1988 August 18-1989 February 17 (Reel R4861, Reel R5555)
    Enable a makerere university professor to attend a consultation with african researchers on the refugee situation in africa
    Uganda
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09050676), 1990 April 01-1992 April 01 (Reel R7216)
    Partial support for a series of case studies on financing economic reform in africa
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09101400), 1991 September 01-1998 August 31 (Reel R7636)
    Support for a graduate fellowship program in refugee studies for thai students
    $153,500.00; $153,500.00
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09250957), 1992 July 01-1997 July 31 (Reel R7770)
    Support for participation of southeast asian refugee practitioners in oxford university's refugee studies program
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09350673), 1993 April 01-1994 December 31 (Reel R6387)
    Project support for conference of refugee research organizations
    McClymont, Mary (Mary E.); O'Cleireacain, Seamus
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09550633), 1995 April 01-1997 March 31 (Reel R7191, Reel R7292)
    Bursaries for east african government refugee agency officials
    $60,240.00; $60,240.00
    Garling, Marguerite L.
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09600798), 1996 April 01-1998 April 30 (Reel R7451)
    Support for a symposium on public interest law in russia and east europe
    Russia and Eastern Europe
    Russia; Europe, Eastern
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09700262), 1997 January 01-1999 July 31 (Reel R8438)
    Gitari, Joseph
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09750478), 1997 March 01-1999 February 28 (Reel R7968)
    Research project on refugee rights in kenya
  - Queen Elizabeth House(UK) (09800104), 1997 October 01-2001 September 30 (Reel R8773)
    Support for the core programs of the refugee studies program
    $820,000.00; $820,000.00
    Global; Refugees--Global--Study and teaching